<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LGBTQ West Island Centre</title>
    <link>https://lgbtqwicentre.org/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on LGBTQ West Island Centre</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Site made by &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:nicolas.martel@outlook.com&#34;&gt;Nicolas Martel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Copyright (c) 2017, LGBTQ West Island Center; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 13:39:24 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://lgbtqwicentre.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About the center</title>
      <link>https://lgbtqwicentre.org/about-the-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 13:39:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbtqwicentre.org/about-the-center/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;On 15 May 2011, Beaconsfield United Church in the West Island of Montreal opened the LGBTQ Youth Centre with the aim of providing a safe and welcoming environment where lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender and questioning young people can meet up, get to know each other, and generally understand themselves better as queer-identified people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Centre is a safe space, which encourages the free exchange of words &amp;amp; ideas. We can’t understand each other (or ourselves) unless we begin with honest &amp;amp; respectful dialogue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are located within the Beaconsfield United Church building. We receive support from the church, an Affirming congregation that explicitly welcomes and celebrates LGBT people. However, the Centre itself has no religious affiliation. All faiths (or lack thereof) are welcome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-mission&#34;&gt;Our Mission&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We see homophobia in our society. We see the longterm detrimental effect on our young people. We see that no programs or centres exist in the West Island to come to their aid. We see this as an immediate need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our mission is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to create a welcoming environment where lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and questioning young people can easily and safely come to meet, talk, ask questions, develop relationships, and understand themselves as queer-identified people – a place to be themselves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to create a safe environment that promotes trust, equality, respect, diversity, openness, and honesty. The centre will have a coordinator who is queer-identified and has a sense of empathy for youth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to completely respect the privacy of everyone involved. All emails, calls, comments or questions will be kept in strictest confidence. Part of this being a safe space is the guarantee of confidentiality; you are safe to talk about anything without fear of any other people finding out about it, unless you choose to do so. This is an essential part of our mission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to open a dialogue within schools and families about queer-identified people and how we can all help to end homophobia through understanding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to provide information and support to parents, families and frineds of queer-identified young people and help them to better understand some of the issues, challenges, achievements and opportunities they may experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to provide a website that provides links to helpful information gathered from across the country, with an emphasis on resources that are easily accessible to West Island teens and young adults.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to empower queer youth to take control, develop leadership skills and get involved in the community, to become informed and inform others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-website&#34;&gt;Our Website&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Blog is a great place to start if you’re curious about what’s been going on lately or just what has been on our minds. Check out our events area to see what’s coming up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resources section provides access to other Montreal Centres, offers guidance for parents &amp;amp; friends, lends support to those coming out and hosts links to many great resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make a donation! Help out lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgendered and questioning youth by donating generously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;drop-in-center&#34;&gt;Drop-In Center&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Drop in center is open Wednesdays &amp;amp; Fridays from 4:00-8:00 PM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;contacting-the-centre&#34;&gt;Contacting the Centre&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to contact the Centre director via phone or email, with the option of arranging a one-on-one visit. All communication whether emails, calls, comments, questions or conversations, are kept private and confidential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you are out, closeted, or somewhere in between – we are with you all the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calendar</title>
      <link>https://lgbtqwicentre.org/calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbtqwicentre.org/calendar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Calendar&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us</title>
      <link>https://lgbtqwicentre.org/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbtqwicentre.org/contact/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;we-are-here-to-help-you&#34;&gt;We are here to help you&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the contacts below to reach out and drop us a line. We’re always happy to answer questions about our workshops, activities, drop in times, homophobia, coming out or anything that may be on your mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that all communication with us will be held in strictest confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;youth-centre&#34;&gt;Youth Centre&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;contact-icons&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;maito:lgbtqyouthcentre@gmail.com&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-envelope-o&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/lgbtqyouthcentre/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-facebook-official&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/LGBTQYouthMTL&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-twitter&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/lgbtqyouthcentremtl&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-instagram&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;rainbow-seniors&#34;&gt;Rainbow Seniors&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;contact-icons&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;maito:wirainbowseniors@gmail.com&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-envelope-o&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/LGBTRainbowSeniorsCentre/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-facebook-official&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/RainbowSeniors&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-twitter&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;parent-support-group&#34;&gt;Parent Support Group&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;contact-icons&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;maito:lgbtqparentsgroup@gmail.com&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-envelope-o&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/ParentsGroupLgbtqYouthCentre/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-facebook-official&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;adult-group&#34;&gt;Adult Group&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;contact-icons&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;maito:lgbtqadultgroup@gmail.com&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-envelope-o&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/LGBTQAdultGroup/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-facebook-official&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parents group</title>
      <link>https://lgbtqwicentre.org/parents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbtqwicentre.org/parents/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;As a parent; has your child recently come out to you and you don’t know how to take it? Is your child transitioning and you are unsure how to show your support or vent your concerns? Do you think your child might be gay or lesbian?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a youth; do you feel like your parents just don’t understand you? Are you tired of trying to talk to your parents about your orientation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our parent support group, which meets on the second Thursday of every month, provides a space for parents and family members to come to discuss their concerns or questions about their family member’s orientation. The parent’s support group is designed to be a judgement free space where we give you the resources to explore resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;drop-in-hours&#34;&gt;Drop-in hours&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Second Thursday of each month - 7:00 to 9:00 p.m.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://lgbtqwicentre.org/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbtqwicentre.org/resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#montreal&#34;&gt;In Montreal and the West Island&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#clergy&#34;&gt;LGBTQ-positive clergy and church congregations in the West Island&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#health&#34;&gt;Health (including mental and sexual)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#addictions&#34;&gt;Addictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seniors group</title>
      <link>https://lgbtqwicentre.org/seniors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbtqwicentre.org/seniors/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The West Island Rainbow Seniors provides a space where Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Trans seniors (50+) can come to meet new people and engage with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We host weekly dinners, shared with the LGBTQ Adult group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;drop-in-hours&#34;&gt;Drop-in hours&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Thursdays - 4:00 to 8:00 p.m.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Young Adult Social</title>
      <link>https://lgbtqwicentre.org/young-adults/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbtqwicentre.org/young-adults/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The newest addition to the West Island LGBTQ Centre, the Young Adult Social (Y.A.S.), is a bi-weekly event that brings together LGBTQ individuals who are trying to balance their rapidly developing lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;drop-in-hours&#34;&gt;Drop-in hours&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Every second Friday - 8:30 to 11:00 p.m.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Youth centre</title>
      <link>https://lgbtqwicentre.org/youth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbtqwicentre.org/youth/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The LGBTQ Youth Centre is a space where high school and CEGEP aged queer youth can come to spend time with likeminded individuals. Our Centre provides a safe space free from the judgment of prejudice that LGBTQ individuals may face in their day to day life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We offer a wide range of events and activities year round; Themed Parties (Halloween, Winter Holiday, Valentines Day.), Annual Gay Proms, Summer and Winter Camps, and many others. We also host fun and engaging workshops, designed to focus on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;drop-in-hours&#34;&gt;Drop-in hours&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Wednesdays &amp;amp; Fridays - 4:00 to 8:00 p.m.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>